Finding aid for WUOM Records, 1914-1982
Bentley Historical Library
- Audio Material, 1930s-1970s
  - Sound Reels (10.5 inch)
    - U-M Sesquicentennial Celebration
      - $55 Million Dollar Campaign: Speeches (Victory Dinner) ([R273B-R274B- R275B]), 1967 December 09; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 29)
        - [Reel 1, Part 1], [8738-SR-123-1-1-1]; (Tape 1 of 2; Speakers include: Frederick Matthai; Gilbert Bursley; Paul Goebel; Herbert Hildebrandt; Harlan H. Hatcher; Michigan Band; Michigan Men's Glee Club.)
        - [Reel 2, Part 1], [8738-SR-123-1-1-2]; (Tape 2 of 2; Speakers include: Frederick Matthai; Gilbert Bursley; Paul Goebel; Herbert Hildebrandt; Harlan H. Hatcher; performances by the Michigan Band and Michigan Men's Glee Club.)
      - University of Michigan Birthday Symposium [Alumni Weekend] (Box 30)
        - "The Right of Free Discussion" / Mike Wallace; Arnold Gingrich; Arthur Miller ([R275B]), 1967 March 02; 2 Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
          - [Reel 1, Part 1], [8738-SR-124-1-1-1]; (Tape 1 of 2; Panel on the topic of "The Right of Free Discussion" during University of Michigan Birthday Symposium (Alumni Weekend) with Mike Wallace; Arnold Gingrich; Arthur Miller.)
          - [Reel 2, Part 1], [8738-SR-124-1-1-2]; (Tape 2 of 2; Question and answer session for panel on the topic of "The Right of Free Discussion" during University of Michigan Birthday Symposium (Alumni Weekend) with Mike Wallace; Arnold Gingrich; Arthur Miller.)
      - Voices of Civilization Lecture Series, October 2-6, 1967 (Major Ceremony IV)
        - Voices of Civilization "The American Racial Question" / Ellison and Gunnar Myrdal, ([R277B]), 1967 October 02; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-125-1-1]; (Recorded October 2, 1967, Broadcast 1967 December 23; Ralph Ellison, African-American author speaks about the "American Racial Problem" and Swedish sociologist Karl Gunnar Myrdal gives his impressions.)
        - Voices of Civilization "The Origins of Life" / Harold Urey ([R278B]), 1967 October 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-125-2-1]; (Recorded October 3, 1967, Broadcast Lecture Hour December 9, 1967. Content is not Harold Urey. James G. Blanks lecturing on Housing and African Americans.)
        - Voices of Civilization "The Formations of the Notions of Speed and Time" / Jean Piaget ([R279B]), 1967 October 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-125-3-1]; (Recording of Jean Piaget Lecture in French & English.)
        - Voices of Civilization "The American Racial Question" / Gunnar Myrdal; Ralph Ellison ([R280B]), 1967 October 04; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-125-4-1-1]; (Tape 1 of 2; Ralph Ellison, African-American author speaks about the "American Racial Problem" and Swedish sociologist Karl Gunnar Myrdal gives his impressions. The event was part of a Lecture Series, October 2-6, 1967.)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-125-4-1-2]; (Tape 2 of 2; Ralph Ellison, African-American author speaks about the "American Racial Problem" and Swedish sociologist Karl Gunnar Myrdal gives his impressions. The event was part of a Lecture Series, October 2-6, 1967)
        - Voices of Civilization "Europe and Asia in American Foreign Policy" / Dean Acheson; Edwin Reischauer ([R282B]), 1967 October 04; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-125-5-1]; (Lecture Series, October 2-6, 1967 (Major Ceremony IV) Recorded October 4, 1967, Broadcast October 5, 1967, Broadcast Lecture Hour December 16, 1967.)
        - "The Birth of an Opera" [lecture] / Luigi Dallapiccola, recorded, October 4, 1967; [R283B] (Box 30)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour December 29, 1967)
        - Voices of Civilization "Memory" / Jean Piaget ([R284B]), 1967 October 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-125-6-1]; (Lecture Series, October 2-6, 1967 (Major Ceremony IV) [lecture] (In French & English.))
        - [Lecture] / [____] Kurylovicz, recorded, October 5, 1967; [R285B] (Box 30)
        - Voices of Civilization "Cities and Their Plight", Convocation / Harlan H. Hatcher, ([R287B]), 1967 October 06; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-125-7-1]; (Lecture Series, October 2-6, 1967, Recorded October 6, 1967, Broadcast Commentary December 12, 1967; [last half is conferring of Honorary Degrees, Dean Acheson, [unknown Polish architect], Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar, Luigi Dallapiccola, Michael E. DeBakey, Theodosius Dobzhansky, Ralph W. Emerson,Raymond Firth, Vladimir Fock, Jerzy Kurylowicz, Karl Gunnar Myardal, Shoji Hamada, Paul G. Hoffman, Severo Ochoa, Jean Piaget, Edwin O. Reischauer, Paul Samuelson, Sir Geoffrey Ingram Taylor, Arne Wilhelm Kaurin Tiselius, Harold Clayton Urey, Marcolino Gomes Candau.)
    - U-M History
    - State and Local History and Events
      - Ann Arbor Fair Housing Ordinance (Proposed): Public Hearing / Ann Arbor Common Council; ([R288B-R289B]), 1963 March 19; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 30)
        - [Reel 1, Part 1], [8738-SR-126-1-1-1]; (Tape 1 of 2; Recording of Ann Arbor Common Council Meeting. Fred Hindeley, Announcer; broadcast March 19, 1963)
        - [Reel 2, Part 1], [8738-SR-126-1-1-2]; (Tape 2 of 2; Recording of Ann Arbor Common Council Meeting.)
  - Sound Discs
    - WUOM: Original Productions
      - Euripides' Orestes: A new dramatic version by the University of Michigan translator; Don Gillis, composer; Orien Dalley, conductor; Jerry Sandler, director, First radio performance, 1960; [D1]; 2 sound discs (4 sides; 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm) (Box 31)
    - WUOM: Program Series
      - "Festival of Song", 1959/60-1970/71; [D2-D8]; 7 phonograph records (12 in., 33 1/3 rpm)
        - Theme Music for Down Story Book Lane, [D9]; 1 phonograph record (12 in., 33 1/3 rpm) (Box 31)
          (test pressing, recorded December 30, 1958)
    - University of Michigan: Ceremonies and Convocations
      - [Acceptance Speech, Baird Carillon Dedication] / Charles Baird; [Nationally broadcast greetings to University of Michigan Alumni Clubs / T. Hawley Tapping, recorded, 1937; [D10]; 1 phonograph record (aluminum acetate; 10 in., 78 rpm) (Box 31)
      - [Address] to Rochester [Alumni Club] / T. Hawley Tapping; [Comments on University of Michigan 100th Anniversary / Arthur L. Cross, recorded, 1937; [D11]; 1 sound discs (2 sides; aluminum acetate; 10 in., 78 rpm)) (Box 31)
      - [Addresses for] 110th Birthday Party of University of Michigan / Alexander G. Ruthven, Clair Hughes, recorded, January 16, 1947; [D12]; 1 phonograph record (aluminum acetate, inside start; 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm) (Box 31)
        (broadcast March 18, 1947)
      - [Comments on University of Michigan 100th Anniversary] / Arthur L. Cross; To the Dallas Alumni January 20, 1938 / T. Hawley Tapping, recorded 1938, [D13]; 1 phonograph record (aluminum acetate; 8 in., 33 1/3 rpm) (Box 31)
        (Cross recording is in poor condition)
      - [Comments re: "Varsity" and the Michigan football team] / Fielding H. Yost; Harry Kipke; Michigan, 1937; [D14]; 1 sound discs (sides 1 and 3; aluminum acetate; 12 in., 78 rpm) (Box 31)
      - Football Preview / Bill Fleming, Fritz Crisler, et al., 1953; [D15]; 2 sound discs (2 sides; 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm) (Box 31)
      - Rose Bowl Greetings / Fritz Crisler; 111th Anniversary greetings / Alexander G. Ruthven, [T. Hawley] Tapping, recorded, 1948; [D16]; 1 phonograph record (aluminum acetate; 10 in. 33 1/3 rpm) (Box 31)
- Printed Material
  Printed Materials are divided into two series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications. The Unit Publications series includes annual reports from 1933-1985, articles about the radio station, brochures, an almost complete run of programming schedules, and specific program publications. The specific program publications include brochures, scores, programs, manuals, newsletters, schedules, and transcripts of original programming from WUOM such as the Festival of Song, Michigan Radio Classroom, Michigan University of the Air, Radio Music Courses, and the WUOM Radio Classroom. The Sub-Unit Publications series includes brochures and a manual from the Package Program Service. The Tape Transcription Service created a list of the Programs Produced by WUOM for Rebroadcasts to Schools in Northern Michigan.
  - Unit Publications
    - Annual and Miscellaneous Reports
      - 1933-1947, 2 volumes (Box 32)
      - 25th Annual Report of the University Broadcasting Service, 1950 (Box 32)
      - 1951-1985, 4 folders (Box 32)
    - Articles, 1926-1965 (Box 32)
    - Brochures
      - Undated, 1944-1989 (Box 32)
      - Long Range Plan for Radio Station WUOM, 1987-1990 (Box 32)
      - Soundprints, [1987] (Box 32)
      - Ten Years of Educational Broadcasting, 1948-1958, [1958] (Box 32)
    - Flyers, [1950] (Box 32)
    - Programs, 1967-1992 (Box 32)
    - Newsleters
      - On the Air, 1997-1999 (Box 32)
      - Michigan radio Quarterly, 2001-2002 (Box 32)
      - Broadcasting Newsletter, 1944 (Box 32)
      - Off Mike, 2002-2004 (Box 32)
    - Prospectus
      - WUOM of the University of Michigan, by Collins Radio Company, Cedar Rapids, Iowa, [1949 ?] (Box 32)
    - Reports
      - Monthly, 1937-1947 (Box 32)
      - A Long Range Plan (Box 32)
    - Schedules
      - Announcement of Radio Programs, Undated, 1935-1944; 1976 (Box 32)
      - On the Air: for the Friends of Michigan Radio, 1997- (Box 32)
      - Program Schedules, 1947-1962; 15 folders (Box 32)
      - Program Guide, 1963-1978; 16 folders (Box 32)
      - Program Guide, 1979-1983; 5 folders (Box 33)
      - Soundprints, 1983-1994; 12 folders (Box 33)
      - Weekly Schedules, Undated; 1937-1938 (Box 33)
    - Specific Program Series Publications
      - Class in Stage and Radio Diction
        - Schedule, 1937-1938 (Box 34)
      - Education for the Veteran
        - Transcripts, 1946 (Box 34)
      - Festival of Song
        - Brochures, Undated (Box 34)
        - Programs
          - The Spring Songfest, 1966-1970 (Box 34)
        - Scores
          - Piano Accompaniment, 1966-1970 (Box 34)
          - Student Song Books, 1950-1970; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - The Great Lakes
        - Manuals
          - Broadcast Handbook for Teachers' Use, 1947 (Box 34)
      - Hobbying at the Piano
        - Scores, 1951 (Box 34)
        - Michigan, My Michigan, 1940-1941 (Box 34)
          (List of Suggested Topics)
      - Michigan Night
        - Transcripts
          - "Michigan Night" Radio Speeches, 1928-1933 (Box 34)
      - Michigan Radio Classroom
        - Manuals
          - Teachers' Manuals, 1953-1970; 7 folders (Box 34)
        - Newsletters
          - The Michigan Radio Classroom News, 1955 (Box 34)
        - Schedules, 1951 (Box 34)
        - Specific Programs
          - Modern Painting: A Series of Twelve Radio Discussions on Modern Painters and Their Work
            - Schedules, 1947 (Box 34)
            - Transcripts, 1947 (Box 34)
      - Michigan University of the Air
        - Manuals
          - Course in the Playing of All Band Instruments, Undated; 1931-1932 (Box 34)
          - Five-week Course in the Playing of All Band Instruments, 1931 (Box 34)
          - A Radio Course for Stringed Instruments: Violin, Viola, Cello, String Bass, 1932 (Box 34)
          - A Radio Course in Singing for Elementary Schools, 1933 (Box 34)
          - Radio Music Course for Band Instruments (Box 34)
        - Scores, 1933-1935; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Radio Music Course for Stringed Instruments
        - Scores, 1933-1951 (Box 34)
      - Radio Programs Given at the University of Michigan
        - Transcripts, 1925-1945; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - WUOM Radio Classroom
        - Manuals, 1952 (Box 34)
  - Sub-Unit Publications
    - Package Program Service
      - Brochures, 1956
        - Manuals Package Program Service to Michigan Radio Stations From Station WUOM, 1961 (Box 34)
    - Tape Transcription Service
      - Programs Produced by WUOM for Rebroadcasts to Schools in Northern Michigan, 1951 (Box 34)